[Music]
hello everyone welcome to business
Central launch event in today's
presentation we would like to present
what's new in business Central
integration with data verse my name is
Sarco and my colleagues Ivan kage for
both product manager for business
Central in the agenda today we'll first
review the data verse integration with
business Central and then my um
colleague Ivan will uh talk about what's
new in data syn and then uh it's my turn
to talk about what's new in Virtual
tables and what's new in business event
so without further Ado let's review uh
data ver
integration so as you know already uh
dataverse is a data storage and
management layer for business
application built on Power Platform that
includes Dynamic 365 sales marketing
field service and customer service
business Central is not built on data
verse but we have extensive Fabrics or
tools to integrate with other first and
thirdparty business application running
on the ters essentially promoting Better
Together scenario through wider and
deeper interaction Within being Central
on those
apps extensive mean we cover all types
of app and system interaction between
business Central and those data verse
apps such as data sync or
synchronization virtual table or
virtualization uh data cut event data
change update or delete events or change
notification and finally business event
which is action
notification Better Together mean
business Central and those data app can
be integrated in such a way that they
can enhance each other essentially
living up to the proverbial um um uh
expression 1 + 1 equal 3 and the way to
do that is to do a wider and deeper
integration uh taking advantage of the
breadth and depth of those compliment
interactions so they become more and
more sticky uh one from the other all
right so let's go quickly uh on the four
complimentary interaction within
Business Center daters the first one is
data sync that replicates data changes
when data is created updated or deleted
between overlapping tables in business
Central and data verse the second one is
virtual tables that enable inbound
interaction from data vers into business
Central using a business Central uh
cruit API but without duplicating data
the third interaction is data cut events
this enables the the reverse Direction
which is the outbound interaction from
business Central to notify other data
verse apps that there are some changes
uh in business Central some data changes
for example it can actually start a
power automate flow using the when a row
is added modified or deleted trigger and
the final interaction is business event
that also enable outban interaction uh
from business Central to notify that
some action are performed on business
Central so other apps in data ver can
react this can also start a power
automate flows using the when an action
is performed trigger so next I would
like to pass it to my um colleague um
Ivan to talk about what's new in data
sync wow these were some really great
diagrams and I really love you know
looking at the bigger picture before
diving into details so today I'll take
you through some of the improvements
that we've done in data sync and sort of
around it right so we'll talk about
linking uh business Central and data ver
environments we'll talk about how you
can add uh additional table and field
mappings and we'll talk a bit about the
new thing that we added we talk about uh
synthetic relations so the first topic
that I want to talk to you today about
is uh using linked uh environments in
data ver integration so why is this
important this is important mainly
because businesses want to keep their
dat data safe and secure and without a
within a specific privacy boundary
admins now have a way of ensuring that
that specific business Central uh
environment can be linked only with a
specific uh data verse environment it
also one of the sort of the side effects
of that is that it actually ensures even
a bit less friction because you don't
have to uh you don't have to choose the
environment you want to connect uh
anymore if the linked environment
exists another addition that we've added
in here is we've added a capability to
add uh table mappings to existing
integration tables that has been a
recurring request from uh our partners
and our customers and right now what you
can do is you can simply uh go and
Define new tables uh that you want to
map you find the key synchronization
parameters such as descript such as
Direction and filters and after that you
can also Define a configuration
templates that are going to be applied
in either of the directions when data
comes in business Central or when the
data comes in uh data verse as well as
with uh table mappings you can also now
add uh field mappings to these new uh
newly created integration table mappings
or to the existing integration table
mappings you define that uh also by
specifying the the parameters for each
of the fields such as uh transformation
rules validation rules and when they
need to be uh
applied there are few things that uh we
need to note uh in here for the table
integration mappings uh what you will
notice is that um you can't actually um
remap or duplicate existing uh
integration table uh mappings because
these are defined uh in code and we
don't want the the custom ones to
actually interfere with with the
existing uh table
mappings uh the similar things uh
similar things applies to uh field
mappings with additional uh with
additional sort of constraint in here we
do support uh most of the simple data
type
uh in the mappings but you will still
need a developer assistance in case you
want to do some uh uh some mapping of of
of lookup Pei fields or you want to
introduce some additional logic that
needs to be executed when the data gets
transferred one way or the other there
are a few other things that I thought it
was sort of uh good to know and good to
uh share uh with our community in here
there are some uh few smaller or minor
improvements that were also added to the
data uh synchronization bit of
integrating with data uh one of the
things that we've added is as you can
see on the picture you now have a
troubleshooting fact box which enables
admins to quickly identify and and
mitigate the issues uh that might have
been uh that might have happened uh
during the synchronization rather than
sifting through the log long long uh
synchronization log and going on
different places right now when you go
to table integration table mappings you
can on the on the level of a specific uh
integration table mapping inspect the
integration errors and uh couple data
synchronization
errors uh one of the other things that
we've made to make uh the Integrations a
bit more robust the operations of
copying the company and copying the
environment now actually do a proper
cleanup uh of synchronization so you
don't get into situations where uh your
data might uh sort of U erroneously show
that it has been coupled uh after you
have copied the company or that you get
the the synchronization errors from The
Source company that you copied and and
so on and the last but not least
important think in uh in these small
things that are good to know is that we
have actually renamed named uh some of
our u connection uh setup Pages uh so uh
we used to have Dynamics uh we used to
have data verse connection setup and
Dynamics Dynamics 365 connection setup
so the data verse connection setup stay
the data verse connection setup but the
Dynamics 365 actually got rename to
Dynamics 365 sales integration setup now
that we also have the integration to
field service which is also named like
that but if you use tell me you will
still be able to uh you will still be
able to find those pages uh the way uh
you are used to finding them and the
last thing that I want to uh say in here
is that we have actually enabled the use
of synthetic relationships uh from
business Central and why is that
important you know and Sandy actually
said there are sort of you know in
general two ways of how you can actually
move the data you can either synchronize
data meaning you will transfer the data
and you can use the
virtualization way of of exposing
business Central data without
transferring the data right and since we
do have a set of uh apis that can
actually be exposed as virtual tables in
in data verse and we know which data we
are syncing it makes sense to basically
rather than go and
customize and add to the to the to the
set of data that gets
synchronized uh rather than doing that
and spending uh developer time on that
you can now actually use the existing
apis to sort of supplement uh that data
that has been uh that has been synced in
in this uh in this particular uh
capability you can simply pick uh the
tables that are being synced you can
pick the virtual table link them using
the couple of fields uh that uh you
specified and as you are guided through
the uh new synthetic relationship
assisted setup
guide and that uh takes us to the demo
so in business Central we'll get to a
data ver connection setup where in the
integration Action Group you can open
integration table mapping there's this
new capability where you can actually
add new table mapping we will call it
work uh work type to p pay type as I
want to link the business Central work
type with the pay type in in field
service for
example uh what I will do in here I will
pick a
table
work type this is a business Central
table and I will pick an integration
table is called pay field service
resource pay
type uh I need to pick the the fields
that uniquely identify the data verse U
the data verse record and I also need to
set the field that is used by the sync
engine to um figure out whether that
data has been modified or uh or not I
can choose in here to sync only coupled
record I will sync everything in here
and under Advan tab the if I click the
advanced button in here I can actually
specify additional filters by creating a
uh
creating a filter for these table these
are very simple tables I don't need any
any filters in either of these
Direction and I can also uh specify the
the configuration templates code uh code
for when the data comes in business
Central and the integration table
configuration template code when the
data uh comes in data verse if I want to
supplement it uh with something now that
we have uh the tables uh and the
integration table mapping uh setting
done I can actually go ahead and proceed
to uh field mappings and in here I will
simply put I want the code to go to the
field that is
called I think it's called name for
example and in here I can let's say
apply uh title case
transformation and let's say I just want
to validate uh this field clicking next
we'll go ahead and uh create the new
integration table mapping it will also
create uh the field
mappings uh the thing with the with a
with a field mappings is that the fields
mappings are by default going to be in U
um inserted as disabled so in order so
the moment when this gets created and
the job for example uh if if you have
been adding fields to an the existing
integration table mapping there could be
a job that is already running so we
wanted to provide you with a bit more
control over um when you actually uh go
and enable these new things that you
added in here and of course after I
click finish there's also a uh the the
the guide actually creates a
synchronization job queue that is going
to run uh the the synchronization okay
now we have the new integration table
mapping in here what you will see these
actually get a flag as a userdefined
mappings and you can actually check the
fields oh what did I select that was the
first one let's select the correct one
if you select the fields here are the
fields uh that are done and what I can
do uh from now on I can simply go ahead
and synchronize modified records after I
have some records that are coupled or
simply run the full synchronization for
this to
initiate uh to initiate the
synchronization mapping
synchronization yes yes we want to run
it
and and and that's uh and that's it for
this part of the
demo so in the next demo uh I will show
you how to actually go and uh set up a
uh synthetic
relations uh I have uh I have Dynamics
365 for sales integration enabled in
here and I've have created some sales
orders and what I want to do in here is
uh I want to uh also add uh shipments to
those sales orders that I have that I'm
already sying first thing that I need to
do is check out uh whether a sales
shipment uh virtual table has been
enabled it has and now I go to uh
synthetic relations where I will create
a new synthetic relation between a uh
sales order um uh sales order table uh
or entity in data worse and a uh sales
shipment uh virtual
table if I click the advanced you will
see uh there's a virtual table uh API
page that is used to list the fields
that I can uh pick and I will map uh
those uh two tables by business Central
order number and the other table
actually has a order order number as
well okay now when I click next if
there's a key already present uh
relationship just gets
created uh I can see that the
relationship has been
added now if I go and switch back uh
have a look at my sales orders
right uh I will uh this is one uh sales
order that I have uh actually already
sent from uh Dynamic 365 for sales to
business Central and I will post some uh
some quantity just to create a shipment
record in here let's say three
and let's go and uh post the
shipment and after the shipment is
posted you can see I already posted one
before when I was preparing a demo and
there's a second one uh that was created
uh in here if I now go and switch to
Dynamics 365 for sales look at that
sales order that I have transferred uh
to to business Central the moment I
created that synthetic relations I now
see I now have this new sales shipments
tab clicking at uh and you can see there
are two shipments in there if I uh click
in in that one since I have the S
shipment lines also enabled it
automatically actually shows the Sal
shipment lines for that table and that's
how easy it is actually to uh uh create
a synthetic relation and use it uh in
your uh in your production in
environments and what you saw that I'm
just a product manager so I didn't do
any coding this time around so that
makes me really
happy and with
that let me hand you off to uh to Sandy
and I feel like that this you know
synthetic relations thing was a perfect
cue for what you want to talk about next
so take it away Sandy uh thanks Ian uh
in this part of the presentation I would
like to show what's new in Virtual
tables so if you remember we have
entered General availability for virtual
table in the last release which is uh 23
Wave 2 and at the same time we also
enter public preview for power pages on
Virtual tables that also happen in the
same release 20 uh 233 Wave 2 release
right so now I would like to show you
what's new in 24 Wave 1 release for
virtual tables we don't have a many
features but we have the small features
that actually have been in high Demand
by many partners and isv who wants to
build virtual tables to support
different companies in business Central
as you remember um there is no company
Concept in data verse so we actually
have to support um um um a way for power
page uh power apps and power pages to
Target different company so in the demo
later I will show several steps the
first step is to show you the standard
global company settings that will be
used by the virtual table plugin uh for
all users and all apps and portals so
that means uh when the global company
setting is set all user and all app will
have the same company right and then uh
we also have um since the beginning a
user specific company setting that can
be used by the virtual tble uh plug-in
to overwrite the global company setting
for all apps and portal so that means
for each user it they can use um uh one
company and this company that uh they
target will be used for all apps and
portal uh that they built or that they
use right so what if they uh the same
user want to use different apps and
different Power uh Power Pages portal
but uh targeting different company this
is where the new feature uh come into
play so we introduced with this release
a data verse shared BC Company ID
execution variable that will be used by
rever virual table plugin to override
both the global and user specific
company settings and I will show you how
to build a custom data verse mapping
plugin and mapping table to set this BC
Company ID shared variable for any
combination of user apps or
portal so before we go to demo let me
show you how this uh um mapping plugin
and table works right in the standard um
uh uh power apps that try to access a
business center virtual tables uh the
the app in this case in this pictures
for example app one it will use data
verse cruit API to Target um um uh
Business Center virtual tables in data
verse and then the virtual table plugin
will translate that data verse crout API
into business Central crout
API and will use uh will Target the
business Central company that has been
configured with the standard Global and
user specific company settings now now
you can actually create a mapping plugin
and table so the mapping PL plugin can
be created to intercept any power apps
or any power Pages portal accessing
selected business Central uh table so
for example I can actually create a
mapping plugin to intercept any request
for data verse uh crout API that access
business Central sales invoice virtual
table using the read API which is a
retrieve or retrieve multiple in data
verse world right and then um then you
can also create a mapping table where we
can actually put the records that map
any combination of users apps and power
Pages portal to their respective
business Central company so the way it
work is for example in the second
picture when app two when user 2 and app
two have a mapping table record that
targets company to when it actually
requests to access um um uh uh sales
invoice table right the mapping plugin
will actually intercept that request and
will set the shared BC Company ID
varable to company to such that when the
when the virtual table plug-in uh picked
up it will use the shared BC Company ID
variables set to company to to translate
data verse cruit API into business
Central cruit API Pi overriding the
global and user specific company
settings so now you know how the mapping
plug-in and mapping table um how it work
how do you actually create the register
and create the uh and um um fill out
fill the the mapping table content right
so there are the there are documentation
in data verse which is like a data verse
plugins and a register plugin
documentation right you will see that um
in that documentation you can actually
use the plug-in registration tool where
can you can actually um uh submit a step
where your plugin for example in this my
example is a I call it the company
mapping plugin that will actually
trigger whenever data verse retrieve or
retrieve multiple um uh request is uh uh
is access is used to access uh sales
invoice business Central virtual table
so you know that whenever you want to
access the sales and voice virtual table
either single row or multiple Row the
plugin will be triggered but when the
plug plugin is a mapping plugin
triggered you want to know when actually
um um it should actually uh uh triggered
right so you have to pick the right
execution stage so in this case we pick
the prevalidation stage such that it
always uh it does its operation before
the actual operation done by the
business Central cruit API right and
then in the mapping table you can create
an entry that match your um uh user and
apps so in this case um in a power apps
you can go to the advanced settings you
can see uh you can use the uni name in
this case this is a prefix CR7 B3 sales
invoice app it's the name that you want
to use to in the mapping table and then
in the mapping table you can create an
entry in this case CR7 B3 sells invoice
app and uh whenever the user is mode
administrator you want to always use
Chronos us so you can actually make any
combination of user and uh and Power app
and use many different um uh many
different
companies all right and finally I just
show you a quick uh screenshot of this
uh the code of the mapping plugin it's
very very simple uh this will be
published after the uh launch event so
you can essentially cut and paste it and
modify it right the yellow part that I
highlighted is actually the part of the
code that will deal with power apps and
then in a different demo I will show you
the part of the code that we'll deal
with with power pages so in the in the
part that we'll deal with power apps
when a power app is uh launch and it try
to access a sales invoice virtual table
this plugin will be triggered and it
will grab the app the app name and then
try to find the app name uh to find uh
try to find a match in the mapping table
if there is any record with the app name
if you find a match then you'll look at
the value of the of the company ID in
that match record and use that company
IB to update the value of the shared
variable which is the BC Company ID when
it's done then uh the mapping plugin
will pass the operation to the uh
virtual table plugin and the virtual
table plugin will use that BC Company ID
to
override uh the global and user specific
company
settings all right let's let's do a demo
all right uh in this demo I will first
show you two different company in
business Central so I will show you the
different sales order and sales invoices
of this company so you can see that um
uh the mapping plugin and M mapping
table that uh we built can actually
Target different companies later so
first company is the the default Kronos
USA you can see the sales order for
Kronos USA there's a bunch of them and
then you can also see the sales
invoices there's a bunch bunch of them
also right now I'm going to switch
company and you will see that the sales
order uh for this new company is
actually has less it uh less uh entries
and also the sales invoice has less
entries let me
switch to my
company so this
one and now you can see the invoices of
the my company will have less uh
entries yeah there's only two right and
then the sales order also have
only one I believe if I remember
correctly yeah you see all right so now
I'm going to the BC
configuration app um in here which is
actually comes with the virtual table uh
plug-in installation and I will show you
the default Global setting uh for
company in here the global setting for
um uh for this environment for all BC is
a Kronos USA right and uh I have
actually created a sales order app that
actually show the sales order and you
can see here the sales order that it
shows is actually all the sales order of
the Kronos USA company right and you can
see the user that used to log into this
app is M administrator so now now I'm
going to change the user specific
setting for M administrator user okay so
here you go to the user entry uh the
user table in data verse and pick the
mod administrator and find the company
default to default on forms and here I
want to set my
company okay and then save so now when
it's finished with save this uh setup of
my company in the user specific company
setting will override the kronis USA in
the global setting you can see here if I
refresh it will actually show the sales
order for my
company you see there's only one sales
order right so now what I'm going to do
is I'm going to show you a mapping table
that can actually be used to overwrite
also the user specific setting for any
combination of user and
apps so in here I have a mapping table
which I called app name company mappings
right and in the first entry is
essentially I'm saying that um the app
name is um CR7 B3 sales inverse iip and
for the user mod administrator when
these two combinations is being um
launched uh in the power apps you always
Target Kronos USA all right so uh to get
this the the name of the app you can
actually go to the editing of the sales
invoice app you can look at the settings
and select advanced settings and you can
see the name of the app right so let's
see the sales invoice app
itself so right now if you uh in the
sales invoice app I have a compy setting
that's set to kronis USA so the sales
invoice will show all the sales invoice
of a kronis USA right now I can actually
change the company setting to my
company so if I switch that go to my
company all right I'm I'm saving so if I
if I go back to the sales insource it
will only show the sales invoice of my
company and you can see there there are
fewer sales invoice right so if you go
back to the table and you can see the
table uh has
been uh updated before it was Kronos USA
now if I refresh it should show that the
mod administrator user and the sales
invoice app is targeting my
company you see all right and that
conclude the demo for uh virtual
tables now in this part of the
presentation I would like to talk about
what's new in business
event if you remember uh business event
was uh uh released in public preview for
about two releases ago 23rd wave 1
release and what's new in this release
in 24 Wave 1 is actually a new UI Pages
for troubleshooting minist events and
also we add more information in the
custom dimension for partner Telemetry
in the demo later I will show the follow
following I will first show uh the four
complementary interaction for dataverse
integration that enrich one of the app
running in data ver in this case is
Dynamics 365 sales and we will enrich
this um uh this uh Dynamic 365 sales
with business Central data and
information right and I will show a
power automate flows that triggered by
data cut uh change update uh create
update and delete and also business
event that will push uh business Central
information into Dynamic 35
sales and then uh I will show the UI
Pages showing the successfully subscribe
and send business event and finally I
will show the parel Telemetry showing
the successfully also subscribe um and
send business
events all right let's go to the demo so
in this demo I'm showing you uh Dynamics
365 sales Hub in here you can see a
familiar account called adum corporation
which is actually a business Central
customer that has been synchronized into
Data verse so the data in here is
actually coming from business Central so
it's using data sync right and then
below that um information you can see
there are two subgrid which is called
business Central sales orders and
business Central sales credit memo those
dat those data are actually virtual
tables so we actually showing a virtual
table
enriching um uh the account in data
verse right and the way you do that is
you're using a syntactic relation in
here you can see there are two synthatic
relation that relates a native account
in data verse with sales credit memo
virtual tables in business Central as
well as a native account in data ver
with a sales order virtual table in um
in Business Center you can see here you
see native and virtual table all right
so another thing that I would like to
show you is this part in um in the
account form in data verse where you can
actually push information regarding that
account so we will actually use uh data
cut events and business event to enrich
the notes section or the timeline
section of this adum Corporation you can
see in the past I have actually uh sent
a data cut event to let uh users know
that there's a sales order created in
business Central and then I send a
business event to show that the uh the
sales order has changed status into
release right and finally I sent another
business event to show that the S order
has been posted so I will do that demo
now oh before that I I will actually
show you the power automate flows that
enable us to do this you can see here in
power automate I have three flows one is
called uh sales order created
notification sales order release
notification and finally sales invoice
posted notification right all of them
are the same essentially it will um
it'll be
triggered the for the sales order
created it'll be trigger when there's a
a change in the data when a row is added
right you can hear here when there's a
new sales order in business
Central this flow will be uh
triggered
and when it's triggered we'll get the
row by um the ID uh the row by ID and
then we use that row by ID to find out
which account row are related to that uh
sales order and we use the the name of
the the company to find out uh which
account um form to push information into
so
the the flow is exactly the same let me
get back
so the flow for sales order created is
the same with this flow for sales order
release or sales invoice posted and you
can see um the same flow except the
different trigger uh the other one is
for um uh data change uh notification
trigger while this one is for with a
action perform trigger that used for
business event for example in here you
can
see you actually want to be triggered
when the sales invoice is posted in uh
in uh business Central so let's do that
let's create a new um let's create a new
sales
order and this I'm going to Target a
datam the Paris
chairs
sorry and
quantity so a new sales order has been
created
you see here open
right sales order
101027 and we should be able actually
seeing here if you refresh the timeline
there should be a information push into
the uh datum Corporation account you see
there's a new sales order been created
now I'm going to trigger a business
event by releasing the sales
order I'm going to release
it it's
released all right if you look at you
look at the power automate flow sales
order
release this should be an an event being
triggered and just 6 second ago it
succeeded so now the the timeline should
also be updated if I refresh there will
be a change in the status of sales
order yep you see so the Sal order
101037 is now released now I'm going to
invoice it
post
okay so it become uh posted sales info
321 and if you go back to the power
automate flow let's see if the sales
invoice posted notification is been
triggered yep it's been triggered right
then that means the uh the account form
in Dynamic sales should be updated sales
infos posted uh
information there you go sales infos has
been posted now all this event not only
push to the dynamic um 365 sales but we
can also uh troubleshoot from the uh UI
Pages you can see here there's a page uh
a new page which is called business
event subscription here you can see that
um I have multiple events that I have
subscribed right
yes you see sales invoice post posted uh
version one customer unblock version one
all different version right and then
like if you look at the for example
customer unblock you can see the
activity lock for that subscription for
example in here the subscription was has
been created um a while back and then
there are three different uh
notification being sent so let's go back
to the sales order release and see if
the the event that's being um triggered
is actually also so um uh registered
here
notification yeah this is the last one
on the 13th of March is a there's no
retry because it's successful and it's
been sent and the same thing for sales
invoice posted you can see the the
notification it's also been triggered
just
now and then um now uh those events are
also pushed into partner tary in app
Insight uh we have I have set up uh my
app insight in this environment you can
see the the Telemetry um uh string uh
that I can add into the business Central
admin Center once I do that I can go to
Azure and look at the parner Telemetry
and uh do um a
query like in here for example for that
that uh event uh customer blocked event
that I subscribed before you can see
there's a custom Dimension and all the
new information has been added
the production the you can see the the
name of the event the version right now
if I want to see what event has been
generated recently I can change the
query there are two business event that
has been sent today first one is um uh
it's sales order
release you can see here sales order
release version one targeting Cronus USA
right and the second one the final one
is all sales invoice
posted you can see
here first in one it's also targeting uh
coronus USA and with that uh we conclude
the demo for um for this session and I
hope you enjoy our uh presentation and I
look forward um to meet you uh in person
in the Q&A session thank you